

About Me

I'm an undergraduate student who's passion is coding and software development. I love to do competitive programming. I have hands on experience in software development and team leadership.

My work during internship has been acknowledged by the respective employer. I am a team player.

If you have a role I fit in, please get in touch.

Work Experience

Intern: Web Developer | June 2017 - September 2017

Comezo Infotech Pvt. Ltd.

Worked as frontend developer.

Languages used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, MySQL, PHP Projects: Developed the company website and 3 more projects.

Company website: http://comezo.in/

- Responsible for developing efficient and mobile responsive website.
- Developed dynamic JavaScript and JQuery codes.Responsible for Search Engine Optimization for the website.
- Developed front end of report for school result.
- Developed website for company's client Preducate.
- Redesigned front of company's product LMS.
- Analysed data of school result and formulated MySQL queries.
- Got introduced with moodle and worked on it.

Freelance Web Developer | October 2017 - January 2018

Pararthya

Worked as Freelance Front end Developer.

Developed the company website: http://pararthya.com/
Languages used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap

- Worked on SEO for the website.
- Integrated email service
- Optimized image size for fast load of website
- Developed dynamic JavaScript code for website

Projects

Hand Written Digits Recognition System - (January 2018)

A machine learning application which recognizes and correctly identify hand written digits. It scans the image of digits and converts them into data.

Technology used: Python, Tensor Flow, MNIST data set My Role: Individual project.

Facial Detection System - (January 2018)

A Facial Detection system is a computer application capable of identifying a person from a digital image or a video frame from a video source.

Technology used: C++, OpenCV

My Role: Individual project.
Future Task: Develop Facial Recognition System

Park Assist - (August 2017 - November 2017)

A mobile application used to help a user by showing nearby parking spaces under the radius of 1 km. The application either takes the current position or the user given address as the search point. The application also provides parking management to the parking owners. The available spaces and booking of a space happen in real time. This is achieved with the use of Firebase.

Technology used: React Native, CSS, JSON, Firebase, draw.io My Role: Both Front-end and back-end, prepared PowerPoint Presentation Future Task: Develop Vendor Dashboard

Teacher Assesssment - (February 2017 - Present)

It is a software tool for evaluating teacher performance based on student feedback. Students will get opportunity to grade their teachers so that university can bring improvements in teaching process of faculty. The software evaluates the performance of teacher based on the inputs provided by the students. This will help the new students to know about the teaching faculty and the university to bring improvements in the faculty.

Technology used: Java core, JavaFX, MySQL, CSS My Role: Front-end, Back-end Future Task: Implement it at my college

Quiz - (December 2016 - June 2018)

A standalone application for conducting multiple choice based quiz or tests where a user can make test and students can give test.

Technology Used: Java Core, Java Swing My Role: Front-end, Back-end Future Task: Implement it at my college

Sudoku Game - (September 2016)
A simple application of Sudoku game.
Technology Used: Java Core, Java Swing
My Role: Front-end, Back-end

♀ New Delhi, India

□ abhishekvasudev7@gmail.com

**** 9582044450

% http://abhishekvasudev.github.io

Skills

Java Core Proficient

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript Intermediate

Bootstrap Proficient

Python Beginner

C & C++ Intermediate

Intermediate

React Native Beginner

PHP & Adobe Photoshop Beginner

Relevent Course Work

Object Oriented Programming

Java Programming

MySQL & Firebase

Algorithm Design and Analysis

Data Structure

Machine Learning
Software Engineering

Advanced Cryptography and Network Security

Database Management System

Advanced Computer Network

Education

B.Tech | Information Technology GGSIPU

2014 - 2018

Aggregate: 82.52%

Senior Secondary(XII)

BVB Mehta Vidyalaya

2013 - 2014 Aggregate: 81.40%

Aggregate. 01.40/0

Secondary(X)

BVB Mehta Vidyalaya

2011 - 2012

Aggregate: 9.2 CGPA (87.40%)

Positions of Responsibility

Team Leader, Smart India Hackathon 2017
Led Team SPI, consisting of 6 members, shortlisted for grand finale

Vice President, Special Projects Initiative(SPI)

Core team member of Special Projects
Initiative(SPI) of IT Department of college.
Conducted inter section IT department Hackathon.

President, Techedge Club

Elected as President of Techedge Club, Computer Society, at Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan's Mehta Vidyalaya. Conducted Dewang Mehta Memorial Inter School IT Competition.

Event Organizer, Innoviz 2016

Organized 2 events at the annual techno-cultural fest, Innoviz 2016, at college.